governmentjobs.com 2019-12-20

# GovernmentJobs | City, State, Federal & Public Sector Jobs

Introduction. The following terms and conditions, together with any documents they expressly incorporate by reference (collectively, these "Terms of Use"), govern your use of services, including any content or functionality offered on or through websites under our control, including www.neogov.com, www.governmentjobs.com, the subdomains and subdirectories of each, and any Add-On Service purchased within a website (collectively referred to as the "Services" for purposes of this Terms of Use), but excluding services that explicitly state they are subject to different terms and conditions. These Terms of Use are entered into by and between you and Governmentjobs.com, Inc. (referred to as "NEOGOV", "we", or "us"). 

"You" access our Services as either a Visitor, Job Seeker, or Personnel. For purposes of this Terms of Use, you are a Visitor if you are just visiting one of our Services. You are a Job Seeker if you hold an account with one or more of our Services for the purpose of receiving and responding to job solicitations. You are Personnel if you are an employee or agent of a Customer (defined below) with authorization to access one or more of our Services on behalf of a Customer, or you hold an account for one or more Services for purposes of accessing employee portals to manage your relationship with a Customer (i.e. your employer).

A "Customer" is defined as an employer or agent of an employer that pays for access to our Services for the purpose of posting job solicitations, recruitment, hiring, onboarding personnel, performance monitoring, training, or other applicable HR services provided by us. If you are a Customer that holds a separately negotiated commercial contract with us that explicitly supersedes or prohibits any end user license or online terms of use, excluding purchases of Add-On Services (see Section 3), the terms and conditions within such commercial contract shall control to the extent of any direct conflict.

Please read the Terms of Use carefully before you start to use the Services.

1\. Provision of Services. By using the Services, executing a document that references them, or by clicking to accept or agree to the Terms of Use when this option is made available to you, you accept and agree to be bound and abide by these Terms of Use and our Privacy Policy incorporated herein by reference. If you do not want to agree to these Terms of Use or the Privacy Policy, you must not access or use the Services. Also, by agreeing to this Terms of Use you waive, to the extent permitted under applicable law, any rights or legal requirements that require an original (non-electronic) signature or the delivery or retention of non-electronic records in order for a contract to be legally binding. You represent and warrant that you are of legal age to form a binding contract with us and meet all of the foregoing eligibility requirements. If you do not meet all of these requirements, you must not access or use the Services.

2\. Accessing the Services and Account Security. Subject to your compliance with these Terms of Use, we grant you a non-exclusive, limited, revocable, personal, non-transferable license to use the applicable Services. Unless NEOGOV has entered into a commercial agreement with a Customer permitting you to use the Services for transactions on behalf of another person, you may only use the Services for transactions on your own behalf, and not on behalf of any other person. If you use the Services on behalf of a Customer or natural person, you represent and warrant that you have obtained all required authorizations and consents from the Customer person. 

We reserve the right to withdraw or amend the Services, and any service or material we provide on the Services, in our sole discretion without notice. We will not be liable if for any reason all or any part of the Services is unavailable at any time or for any period. From time to time, we may restrict access to some parts of the Services, or the entire Services, to Visitors, Job Seekers, or Personnel. You are responsible for ensuring that all persons who access the Services through your account are aware of these Terms of Use and comply with them.

To access the Services or some of the resources it offers, you may be asked to provide certain registration details or other information. It is a condition of your use of the Services that all the information you provide on the Services is correct, current, and complete. You agree that all information you provide to register with the Services or otherwise, including but not limited to through the use of any interactive features on the Services, is governed by the NEOGOV Privacy Policy [www.neogov.com/privacy-policy](https://www.neogov.com/privacy-policy) and you consent to all actions we take with respect to your information consistent with our Privacy Policy. Terms not defined herein shall retain their meaning as set forth in the NEOGOV Privacy Policy.

If you choose, or are provided with, a user name, password, or any other piece of information as part of our security procedures, you must treat such information as confidential, and you must not disclose it to any other person or entity. You also acknowledge that your account is personal to you and agree not to provide any other person with access to the Services or portions of it using your user name, password, or other security information. 

You agree to (i) notify us immediately of any unauthorized access to or use of your user name or password or any other breach of security, investigate such breach or such potential breach, (ii) assist us using commercially reasonable efforts in maintaining confidentiality, and (iii) assist us as reasonably necessary to enforce our rights and to enable us to comply with any state or federal law requiring the provision of notice of any security breach with respect to any personally identifiable information of the affected or impacted data subjects. You also agree to ensure that you exit from your account at the end of each session. You should use particular caution when accessing your account from a public or shared computer so that others are not able to view or record your password or other personal information. We have the right to disable any user name, password, or other identifier, whether chosen by you or provided by us, at any time if, in our opinion, you have violated any provision of these Terms of Use.

3\. Add-On Services; Payment.

a. Generally. You may be required to pay fees to access certain add-on features within the Services ("Add-On Service(s)"). Unless otherwise stated by NEOGOV, Add-On Services are governed by the NEOGOV Services Agreement terms most recently published prior to the purchase or renewal of an Add-On Service, as well as these Terms of Use, Service Specifications, and applicable Schedules incorporated therein (available at: [www.neogov.com/service-specifications](https://www.neogov.com/service-specifications)). Where the terms of this Section (Add-On Services; Payment) conflict with the NEOGOV Services Agreement, this Section shall control. Add-On Services may only be available through one or more of our Services and Add-On Services may not be available for all End Users or Customers. 

b. Payment Authorization. You agree to pay to NEOGOV any fees for each Add-On Service you purchase in accordance with the pricing and payment terms presented to you for that Add-On Service. All Add-On Service fees are in U.S. dollars and are non-refundable. If NEOGOV changes the fees for all or part of the Services, including by adding fees or charges, NEOGOV will provide you notice of those changes. If you do not accept the changes, NEOGOV may discontinue providing the applicable part of the Services to you. 

c. Payment Methods. 

i. Debit/Credit Cards. By providing debit or credit card account information through or to the Services, you represent, warrant, and covenant that: (1) you are legally authorized to provide such information to us; (2) you are legally authorized to perform payments from the debit or credit card account(s); (3) the credit card information you provide is correct and you will promptly notify NEOGOV of any changes to such information; and (4) such action does not violate the terms and conditions applicable to your use of such debit or credit card account(s) or applicable law. When you authorize a payment using a debit or credit card account via the Services, you represent, warrant, and covenant that there are sufficient funds or credit available to complete a payment using the debit or credit card account. NEOGOV’s authorized third-party payment processor will charge the payment method you specified at the time of purchase. You authorize NEOGOV to charge all fees as described in these Terms of Use for the Services you select to that payment method, and you authorize our third-party payment processor to use information you provide to process payments, manage debit and credit card information and detect and prevent fraud.

ii. Alternate Payment. In lieu of purchasing Add-On Services via Debit or Credit card, NEOGOV may provide you the option to receive a bill or invoice for payment by alternate means. NEOGOV may align a billing or invoice term with one of your other active Services. Should you elect to receive a bill or invoice for Add-On Service payments, Add-On Service Fees are due net thirty (30) from receipt of NEOGOV bill or invoice. 

d. Add-On Service Subscriptions. The Add-On Services may include features that allow for automatically recurring payments for periodic charges ("Add-On Subscription"). Unless otherwise agreed by NEOGOV, Add-On Subscriptions will be billed in advance on an annual recurring, periodic basis. NEOGOV may also provide pro-rated pricing terms and align Add-On Subscription invoice or billing with SaaS Subscriptions. If you decide to activate an Add-On Subscription, you authorize NEOGOV to periodically charge, on a going-forward basis and until cancellation of the recurring payments, all accrued sums on or before the payment due date for the accrued sums. The Add-On Service Subscription Term is a continuous and non-divisible commitment for the full duration of the term regardless of any invoice schedule. The Subscription will commence upon the date you activate or use the Add-On Service. The Subscription will continue unless and until you cancel your Subscription, or we terminate it. You must cancel your Add-On Subscription before it renews in order to avoid billing of the next periodic subscription fee to your account. We will bill the periodic Subscription Fee to the payment method you provide to us during registration (or to a different payment method if you change your payment information). NEOGOV may change the Subscription Fee for any subsequent Subscription period but will provide you notice of any increase before it applies. Unless otherwise stated in a commercial agreement we negotiated with a Customer, you may cancel an Add-On Subscription by contacting us at: [accounting@neogov.com](mailto:accounting@neogov.com), [customersupport@neogov.com](mailto:customersupport@neogov.com), or alternative means expressly presented to you within the Services. You may cancel auto-renewal on your Add-On Service Subscription at any time, in which case your Add-On Service Subscription will continue until the end of that billing cycle before terminating. 

e. Taxes. Unless otherwise stated, you are responsible for any taxes (other than NEOGOV’s income tax) or duties associated with the sale of the Services, including any related penalties or interest (collectively, "Taxes"). You will pay NEOGOV for the Services without any reduction for Taxes.

f. Purchase Order. If you issue a purchase order, then it shall be for the full amount, and NEOGOV hereby rejects any additional or conflicting terms appearing in a purchase order or any other ordering materials submitted by you, and conditions assent solely based on the terms and conditions this Terms of Use and NEOGOV Services Agreement as offered by NEOGOV. You agree that a failure to provide NEOGOV with a corresponding purchase order shall not relieve you of your obligations to provide payment to NEOGOV.

4\. Termination/Changes to Agreement. Unless otherwise stated herein or as stated in a commercial agreement negotiated between us and a Customer, you may terminate your account at any time. If you terminate your account, you remain obligated to pay all outstanding fees, if any, incurred prior to termination relating to your use of the Services. If you violate any provision of these Terms of Use, your permission from NEOGOV to use the Services will terminate automatically. In addition, NEOGOV may in its sole discretion terminate your account on the Services or suspend or terminate your access to the Services at any time for any reason, with or without notice. NEOGOV may alter, suspend or discontinue the Services or any portion of the Services without notice. NEOGOV will not be liable whatsoever for any change to the Services or any suspension or termination of your access to or use of the Services. NEOGOV reserves the right to revise, change, or update these Terms of Use at any time in its sole discretion on a going-forward basis. All changes are effective immediately when we post them and apply to all access to and use of the Services thereafter. Your continued use of the Services after updates are effective will represent your agreement to the revised version of these Terms of Use. Your continued use of the Services after the effectiveness of such changes will constitute acceptance of and agreement to any such changes. You further waive any right you may have to receive specific notice of such changes to these Terms of Use. You are responsible for regularly reviewing these Terms of Use.

5\. Intellectual Property Rights. The Services and its entire contents, features, and functionality (including but not limited to all information, software, Service Specifications, text, displays, images, video, and audio, and the design, selection, and arrangement thereof)(the "NEOGOV Content") are owned by NEOGOV and are protected by United States and international copyright, trademark, patent, trade secret, and other intellectual property or proprietary rights laws. These Terms of Use permit you to use the Services for your personal, non-commercial use only, and in the case of Customers, for internal business use only. You must not reproduce, distribute, modify, create derivative works of, publicly display, publicly perform, republish, download, store, license, transfer, sell or transmit any of the material on our Services. You are granted a revocable, non-exclusive, non-assignable, and non-transferable license to access use the Services. Nothing in these Terms of Use shall be construed as granting to you a license to NEOGOV Content under any copyright, trademark, patent, or other intellectual property right except as expressly set forth herein.

Re-use of any of NEOGOV’s Service Specifications for any purpose is strictly prohibited without our prior written permission. Please direct any requests for permission to [support@GovernmentJobs.com](mailto:%20support@GovernmentJobs.com).

You must not:

a. Modify copies of any materials from the Services or modify, create derivative works from, distribute, publicly display, publicly perform, or sublicense the Services except as expressly permitted by this Terms of Use.

b. Use any illustrations, photographs, video or audio sequences, or any graphics separately from the accompanying text.

c. Delete or alter any legal notices, copyright, trademark, or other proprietary rights notices from copies of materials from this site.

d. Reverse engineer, decompile, disassemble, or otherwise attempt to discover or directly access the source code or any underlying ideas or algorithms of any portions of the Services or any underlying software or component thereof.

e. Aggregate, copy, or duplicate in any manner any of the content or information available from any our Services, including expired job postings, unless authorized by us.

f. Access or use for any commercial purposes any part of the Services or any services or materials available through the Services.

No right, title, or interest in or to the Services or any content on the Services is transferred to you, and all rights not expressly granted are reserved by us. Any use of the Services not expressly permitted by these Terms of Use is a breach of these Terms of Use and may violate copyright, trademark, and other laws.

6\. Trademarks. "NEOGOV," "GovernmentJobs.com," "CareerNow," "Career Pages," and certain other names or logos are our trademarks, and all related product and service names, design marks, and slogans are our trademarks or service marks, excluding the marks of our partners. You must not use such marks without our prior written permission. We also retain the rights in the designated color schemes and column names provided within the Services. The "look" and "feel" of the Services (including color combinations, button shapes, layout, design, and all other graphical elements not uploaded or implemented by Customers) are also our trademarks or copyrights. 

7\. Prohibited Uses. You may use the Services only for lawful purposes and in accordance with these Terms of Use. You agree not to use the Services:

a. In any way that violates any applicable federal, state, local, or international law or regulation (including, without limitation, any laws regarding the export of data or software to and from the US or other countries).

b. For the purpose of exploiting, harming, or attempting to exploit or harm minors in any way by exposing them to inappropriate content, asking for personally identifiable information, or otherwise.

c. For the unlawful use of any personally identifiable information of other users of which you may be exposed to.

d. To send, knowingly receive, upload, download, use, or re-use any material that does not comply with the Content Standards set out in these Terms of Use.

e. To transmit, or procure the sending of, any advertising or promotional material without our prior written consent, including any "junk mail", "chain letter", "spam", or any other similar solicitation.

f. To impersonate or attempt to impersonate NEOGOV, a NEOGOV employee, another user, or any other person or entity.

g. To engage in any other conduct that restricts or inhibits anyone’s use or enjoyment of the Services, or which, as determined by us, may harm NEOGOV or users of the Services or expose them to liability.

h. Use the communication features in a manner that adversely affects the availability of its resources to other users (e.g. excessive shouting, use of all caps, or flooding continuous posting of repetitive text).

i. Additionally, unless authorized by us, you agree not to:

j. Use the Services in any manner that could disable, overburden, damage, or impair the site or interfere with any other party’s use of the Services, including their ability to engage in real time activities through the Services.

k. Use any robot, spider, or other automatic device, process, or means to access the Services for any purpose, including monitoring or copying any of the material on the Services.

l. Use any manual process to monitor or copy any of the material on the Services or for any other unauthorized purpose without our prior written consent.

m. Use any device, software, or routine that interferes with the proper working of the Services.

n. Introduce any viruses, Trojan horses, worms, logic bombs, or other material that is malicious or technologically harmful.

o. Attack the Services via a denial-of-service attack or a distributed denial-of-service attack including via means of overloading, "flooding," "mailbombing," or "crashing,".

p. Post any incomplete, false, or inaccurate résumé information or information which is not your own accurate résumé.

q. Respond to any employment opportunity for any reason other than to apply for the job.

r. Access the Services in order to build, assist, or facilitate the assembly of a competitive product or service, to build a product using similar ideas, features, functions, or graphics of the System, or to copy any ideas, features, functions, or graphics of the Services.

If your use of the Services requires you to comply with industry-specific regulations applicable to such use, you will be solely responsible for such compliance, unless NEOGOV has agreed with you otherwise. You may not use the Services in a way that would subject NEOGOV to those industry-specific regulations without obtaining NEOGOV"s prior written agreement. For example, you may not use the Services to collect, protect, or otherwise handle "protected health information" (as defined in 45 C.F.R. §160.103 under United States federal regulations) without entering into a separate business associate agreement with NEOGOV that permits you to do so.

Your level of access is limited to ensure your access is no more than necessary to perform your legitimate tasks or assigned duties. If you believe you are being granted access that you should not have, you must immediately notify NEOGOV.

8\. Security Rules of Behavior.

a. You must follow proper logon/logoff procedures. You must promptly logoff when session access is no longer needed. If a logoff function is unavailable, you must close your browser. Never leave your computer unattended while logged into the system.

b. You must report all security incidents or suspected incidents (e.g., lost passwords, improper or suspicious acts) related to NEOGOV Services to NEOGOV.

c. You must not establish any unauthorized interfaces between systems, networks, and applications owned by NEOGOV.

d. Your access to Services and networks owned by NEOGOV may be governed by the Privacy Act, 5 U.S.C. 552a, if the applicable NEOGOV system maintains individual Privacy Act information. Your access to NEOGOV systems constitutes your consent to the retrieval and disclosure of the information within the scope of your authorized access, subject to the Privacy Act, and applicable state and federal laws.

e. You must not process U.S. classified national security information on the Services.

f. You must ensure that Web browsers use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) version 3.0 (or higher) and Transport Layer Security (TLS) 1.0 (or higher). SSL and TLS must use a minimum of 128-bit, encryption. 

g. You must ensure that your web browser is configured to warn about invalid site certificates.

h. You must ensure that web browsers warn if the user is changing between secure and non-secure mode.

i. You must ensure that your web browser window used to access Services owned by NEOGOV is closed before navigating to other sites/domains.

j. You must ensure that your web browser checks for a publisher’s certificate revocation.

k. You must ensure that your web browser checks for server certificate revocation.

l. You must ensure that web browser checks for signatures on downloaded files.

m. You must ensure that web browser empties/deletes temporary Internet files when the browser is closed.

n. You understand that any person who obtains information from a computer connected to the Internet in violation of an employer’s computer-use restrictions is in violation of the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act.

9\. Monitoring and Enforcement; Termination. You agree that we may monitor the Services to (1) comply with any applicable laws, regulations, or other government requests, (2) operate the Services or to protect itself and its users and members, and (3) for such other purposes as it may deem reasonably necessary or appropriate from time to time. More specifically, we have the right to:

a. Remove or refuse to post any User Contributions for any or no reason in our sole discretion.

b. Take any action with respect to any User Contribution that we deem necessary or appropriate in our sole discretion, including if we believe that such User Contribution violates the Terms of Use, including the Content Standards, if we believe that such information could create liability for us, damage our brand or public image, or cause us to lose users or (in whole or in part), the services of our ISPs or other suppliers, if we believe the User Contribution is abusive, disruptive, offensive, illegal, violates the rights of, or harms or threatens the safety of users or public, infringes any intellectual property right, or violates the law. 

c. Disclose your identity or other information about you to any third party who claims that material posted by you violates their rights, including their intellectual property rights or their right to privacy.

d. Take appropriate legal action, including without limitation, referral to law enforcement, for any illegal or unauthorized use of the Services.

e. Terminate or suspend your access to all or part of the Services for any or no reason, including without limitation, any violation of these Terms of Use.

We have the right to cooperate fully with any law enforcement authorities or court order requesting or directing us to disclose the identity or other information of anyone posting any materials on or through the Services. YOU WAIVE AND HOLD HARMLESS GOVERNMENTJOBS.COM, INC. AND ITS AFFILIATES, LICENSEES, AND SERVICE PROVIDERS FROM ANY CLAIMS RESULTING FROM ANY ACTION TAKEN BY ANY OF THE FOREGOING PARTIES DURING, OR TAKEN AS A CONSEQUENCE OF, INVESTIGATIONS BY EITHER GOVERNMENTJOBS.COM, INC. OR LAW ENFORCEMENT AUTHORITIES.

Notwithstanding the forgoing, we are not responsible for screening, policing, editing, or monitoring postings and encourages all users to use reasonable discretion and caution in evaluating or reviewing any post. We assume no liability for any action or inaction regarding transmissions, communications, or content provided by any user or third party. We have no liability or responsibility to anyone for performance or nonperformance of the activities described in this section. 

10\. Content Standards. These Content Standards apply to any and all User Contributions and use of the Services. User Contributions must in their entirety comply with all applicable federal, state, local, and international laws and regulations. Without limiting the foregoing, User Contributions must not:

a. Contain any material that is defamatory, obscene, indecent, abusive, offensive, harassing, violent, hateful, inflammatory, or otherwise objectionable.

b. Promote sexually explicit or pornographic material, violence, or discrimination based on race, sex, religion, nationality, disability, sexual orientation, or age.

c. Infringe any patent, trademark, trade secret, copyright, or other intellectual property or other rights of any other person.

d. Violate the legal rights (including the rights of publicity and privacy) of others or contain any material that could give rise to any civil or criminal liability under applicable laws or regulations or that otherwise may be in conflict with these Terms of Use and our Privacy Policy.

e. Be likely to deceive any person.

f. Promote any illegal activity, or advocate, promote, or assist any unlawful act.

g. Cause annoyance, inconvenience, or needless anxiety or be likely to upset, embarrass, alarm, or annoy any other person.

h. Impersonate any person or misrepresent your identity or affiliation with any person or organization.

i. Involve commercial activities or sales, such as contests, sweepstakes, and other sales promotions, barter, or advertising.

j. Give the impression that they emanate from or are endorsed by us or any other person or entity, if this is not the case.

In addition, you shall be solely responsible for the legality, accuracy and completeness of all records, data, and information provided, submitted, or uploaded by you in connection with this Terms of Use or use of the Services. 

11\. User Contributions. The Services may contain message boards, forums, bulletin boards, and job boards, (collectively, "Interactive Services") that allow users to post, submit, publish, display, or transmit to other users or other persons (hereinafter, "post") materials or content, including feedback (collectively, "User Contributions") on or through the Services. All User Contributions must comply with the Content Standards set out in these Terms of Use. Any User Contribution you post to the site will be considered non-confidential and non-proprietary. You represent that you have all necessary rights to make a post, and you also acknowledge that we have no control over the extent to which any idea or information may be used by any party or person once it is posted or displayed. By providing any User Contribution on the Services, you grant us and our affiliates a royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable, transferable, non-exclusive right and license for us to adopt, publish, reproduce, disseminate, transmit, distribute, copy, use, create derivative works, and display (in whole or in part) worldwide, or act on such feedback without additional approval or consideration, in any form, media, or technology now known or later developed for the full term of any rights that may exist in such content, and you hereby waive any claim to the contrary. Notwithstanding this right and license, it is understood that by merely permitting your information, content, and materials to appear on the Services, we do not become a publisher of such information, content, and materials and is merely functioning as an intermediary to enable you to provide and display a posting. Moreover, we assume no responsibility for the deletion of or failure to store any posting and recommends that you do not post, display, or transmit any confidential or sensitive information.

We are under no obligation to edit or control User Contributions and will not be in any way responsible or liable for any User Contributions. You understand that when using the Services, you may be exposed to User Contributions of other users and acknowledge that User Contributions may be inaccurate, offensive, indecent, or objectionable. You agree to waive, and do waive, any legal or equitable right or remedy you may have against NEOGOV with respect to User Contributions. NEOGOV expressly disclaims any and all liability in connection with User Contributions. If notified by a user or content owner that User Contributions allegedly do not conform with these Terms of Use, NEOGOV may investigate the allegation and determine in NEOGOV’s sole discretion whether to remove the User Contributions, which NEOGOV reserves the right to do at any time and without notice.

You understand and acknowledge that you are responsible for any User Contributions you submit or contribute, and you, not NEOGOV, have full responsibility for such content, including its legality, reliability, accuracy, and appropriateness. We are not responsible or liable to any third party for the content or accuracy of any User Contributions posted by you or any other user of the Services.

12\. E-Signatures.

a. E-Signature Provisioning & Consent. NEOGOV E-Forms and other electronically signed services ("E-Signatures") are provided by NEOGOV for two counterparties (generally a government employer (the "sending party") subscribing to NEOGOV Services and a Personnel or Job Seeker) to electronically sign documents. If you use E-Signatures offered by NEOGOV, you agree to the statements set forth in this Section. Whenever you sign a document using E-Signatures you affirmatively consent to using electronic signatures via the E-Signatures and consent to conducting electronic business transactions. You also confirm that you are able to access the E-Signatures and the document you are signing electronically. When using E-Signatures for a document, your consent applies only to the matter(s) covered by that particular document.

b. Right to Opt-Out of E-Signatures. You are not required to use E-Signatures or accept electronic documents provided thereby. If you are a Job Seeker or Personnel and you choose to not use E-Signatures, you may still sign the document manually by notifying the sending party that you are choosing to do so and by obtaining a non-electronic copy of the document. NEOOGV assumes no responsibility for providing you with a non-electronic version of the document. In the event you are choosing to sign the document manually, do not use E-Signatures to sign the document or to return the document to the sending party.

c. Electronic Download. If you have signed a document electronically using E-Signatures and transmitted it back to the sending party, NEOGOV provides the opportunity to download and print a paper copy of the document at no charge. If you later withdrawn your consent to using E-Signatures, please notify the sending party and stop using E-Signatures. Note that the decision to stop using E-Signatures after you have already used it does not change the legality of the documents you have previously signed using an electronic signature.

d. E-Signature Validity. PLEASE NOTE THAT NEOGOV’S STATEMENTS CONTAINED HEREIN OR ELSEWHERE CONCERNING THE VALIDITY OF ELECTRONIC DOCUMENTS AND/OR THE SIGNATURE LINES OF DOCUMENTS THAT ARE ELECTRONICALLY SIGNED ARE FOR INFORMATIONAL PURPOSES ONLY; THEY SHOULD NOT BE CONSTRUED AS LEGAL ADVICE. UNDER FEDERAL AND STATE LAWS GOVERNING ELECTRONIC SIGNATURES, ELECTRONIC SIGNATURES ON CERTAIN TYPES OF AGREEMENTS ARE NOT ENFORCEABLE. NEOGOV HEREBY DISCLAIMS ANY RESPONSIBILITY FOR ENSURING THAT DOCUMENTS ELECTRONICALLY SIGNED THROUGH E-SIGNATURE’S ARE VALID OR ENFORCEABLE UNDER THE LAWS OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, ANY PARTICULAR STATE, OR ANY OTHER LEGAL JURISDICTION. YOU SHOULD CONSULT WITH LEGAL COUNSEL CONCERNING THE VALIDITY OR ENFORCEABILITY OF ANY DOCUMENT YOU MAY SIGN ELECTRONICALLY USING NEOGOV’S E-SIGNATURE’S.

13\. Text Message and Email Communications. We may offer you the opportunity to receive text message and email notifications regarding notices, reminders, status updates, support, administrative message and disclosures, or other related human resource related notices from us or our Customers. Communications through these methods may be routed through a third-party service.

SMS messages will be sent to you strictly in accordance with your preferences, and only after you have explicitly opted in. If you change your mind at any time, and no longer wish to receive SMS messages, reply to a message with the word "OPTOUT" in all capital letters. Afterwards, should you choose to begin receiving messages again, reply with the word "OPTIN" in all capital letters. Job Seekers may also control their receipt of SMS messages through their Job Seeker Account preferences, by contacting the Customer whom the text message pertains to, or by notifying NEOGOV Support. 

Should you allow SMS messages sent to you by NEOGOV or NEOGOV Customers, you agree to accept such text messages on your mobile phone including messages sent by automated telephone dialing system. You certify that you are the owner of the mobile phone entered or are authorized to use this mobile phone to receive SMS. 

You are responsible for all mobile carrier data or text message charges resulting from your use of the Services, including from any notifications provided by the Services. The number of messages you receive will vary depending on the number of jobs you applied to, jobs you searched for, or the number Customers you allow to contact you. You may receive a text message confirming your subscription. NEOGOV reserves the right to suspend or terminate your SMS messages for any reason, with or without notifying you.

Since these text message services depend on the functionality of third-party providers, there may be technical delays on the part of those providers. NEOGOV may make commercially reasonable efforts to provide alerts in a timely manner with accurate information, but cannot guarantee the delivery, timeliness, or accuracy of the content of any alert. NEOGOV shall not be liable for any delays, failure to deliver, or misdirected delivery of any alert; for any errors in the content of an alert; or for any actions taken or not taken by you or any third party in reliance on an alert. If your mobile number changes, you are responsible for informing the Customer of that change. NEOGOV MAKES NO WARRANTIES OR REPRESENTATIONS OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS, STATUTORY OR IMPLIED AS TO: (i) THE AVAILABILITY OF TELECOMMUNICATION SERVICES FROM YOUR PROVIDER; (ii) ANY LOSS, DAMAGE, OR OTHER SECURITY INTRUSION OF THE TELECOMMUNICATION SERVICES; AND (iii) ANY DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES OR FAILURE TO TRANSMIT ANY DATA, COMMUNICATIONS OR SETTINGS CONNECTED WITH THE SERVICES.

14\. Copyright Infringement. If you believe that any User Contributions violate your copyright, please notify support as specified in this Terms of Use. It is the policy of NEOGOV to terminate the user accounts of repeat infringers.

15\. Reliance on Information Posted. The information presented on or through the Services is made available solely for general information purposes. We do not warrant the accuracy, completeness, or usefulness of this information. Any reliance you place on such information is strictly at your own risk. We disclaim all liability and responsibility arising from any reliance placed on such materials by you or any other visitor to the Services, or by anyone who may be informed of any of its contents. 

16\. Changes to the Services. We may update the content on the Services from time to time, but its content is not necessarily complete or up-to-date. Any of the material on the Services may be out of date at any given time, and we are under no obligation to update such material.

17\. Information About You and Your Visits to the Services. All information we collect on the Services is subject to our Privacy Policy [www.neogov.com/privacy-policy](https://www.neogov.com/privacy-policy). By using the Services, you consent to all actions taken by us with respect to your information in compliance with the Privacy Policy.

18\. Jobseeker Profile. Job Seekers maintain rights in the personal information that make up their Account and Job Seeker Profile. However, Job Seekers do not have ownership rights in the Account of Profile itself. If you delete your account or your account is terminated, all your Profile and Account information, including resumes, profiles, cover letters, saved jobs, and questionnaires may be marked as deleted and may be deleted from NEGOOV databases. Information may continue to be available for some period of time because of delays in propagating such deletion. We reserve the right to maintain certain data after termination where it is necessary to comply with the law. We periodically deletes inactive accounts and reserves the right to delete your account and all of your information. Deletion of your Account or Job Seeker Profile will not delete applications you previously submit to Customers through the Services. 

19\. Relay of Content. NEOGOV relays content including but not limited to resumes, cover letters, applications, messages, questionnaire answers, responses, offer letters and other materials. You acknowledge that you are asking NEOGOV to send this content on your behalf. We process, monitor, review, store and analyze such content, for data analysis, security, quality control, enforcement of the Terms of Use, content moderation, and to improve the Services. As a result, or due to technical malfunction, in certain circumstances such content may be delayed or may not be delivered to the intended recipient. NEOGOV may notify you in such an event. By using the Services, you acknowledge that this activity is necessary for maintaining the quality and provisioning of the Services.

20\. Linking to the Services and Social Media Features. You may link to our homepage, provided you do so in a way that is fair and legal and does not damage our reputation or take advantage of it, but you must not establish a link in such a way as to suggest any form of association, approval, or endorsement on our part without our express written consent. We may disable all or any social media features and any links at any time without notice in our discretion.

21\. Links and Third-Party Content on the Services. If the Services contains links to other sites and resources provided by third parties, these links are provided for your convenience only. This includes links contained in advertisements, including banner advertisements and sponsored links. We have no control over the contents of those sites or resources and accept no responsibility for them or for any loss or damage that may arise from your use of them. We do not control these services and are not responsible for their availability, content, or any malware accessed through them. Your correspondence or any other dealings with third parties found on the Services are solely between you and such third party. Accordingly, we expressly disclaim responsibility and liability for all third-party provided materials, programs, products, and services contained on or accessed through the Services, and you agree that we shall not be responsible for any loss or damage of any sort incurred as a result of any such dealings or as the result of the presence of such third parties on the Services. If you decide to access any of the third-party websites linked to the Services, you do so entirely at your own risk and subject to the terms and conditions of use for such websites. You are advised to read all terms and conditions of any third-party service.

The Services may include content provided by third parties, including materials provided by other users, aggregators, and/or reporting services. All statements and/or opinions expressed in these materials, and all articles and responses to questions and other content, other than the content provided by us, are solely the opinions and the responsibility of the person or entity providing those materials. These materials do not necessarily reflect NEOGOV’s opinion. We are not responsible, or liable to you or any third party, for the content or accuracy of any materials provided by any third parties.

22\. Additional Terms for Third-Party Services. 

a. Generally. The Services include links to third-party products, services and web sites, as well as materials provided by third parties, and may include functionality that allows for the distribution of your personal information to third parties not under NEOGOV’s control (each, a "Third-Party Provider"). Third-Party Providers are solely responsible for their services. You are responsible for your use and submission of information to any third-party, and your dealings or business conducted with any third party arising in connection with the Services are solely between you and such third party. Your use of third-party sites, services, or products may be subject to associated third-party terms of use and privacy policies or other agreements, which you are solely responsible for complying with. By using a tool that allows for your information to be transferred, you agree that NEOGOV may transfer the applicable information to the applicable Third-Party Provider.

b. Specific Third-Party Providers.

Background Checks. Some of the Services allow users to use our third-party background check partner’s services to submit an application and background check to a Customer. If you are a Job Seeker or Personnel using the background check services, you authorize NEOGOV to obtain your background check report, including criminal and eviction history, and to share that information with Customers you submit an application to, and agree to the background check companies terms of use or related end user agreement available at the background check companies’ website. If you are Personnel or other Customer agent using the background check services on behalf of a Customer, you agree to use the background check reports in compliance with law and agree to the background check companies terms of use or related end user agreement available at the background check companies’ website.

Stripe. Some of the Services allow you to use Stripe to make payments. Your use of Stripe is subject to the applicable Stripe Terms of Service found at [stripe.com/connect/legal](https://stripe.com/connect/legal).

Plivo. Some of the Services allow you to send or receive text messages through Plivo, Inc. If you are Personnel or other Customer agent using the text messages services on behalf of a Customer, you agree to use the text message services in compliance with law and agree to the Plivo Acceptable Use Policy available at [www.plivo.com/aup/](https://www.plivo.com/aup).

23\. Geographic Restrictions. The owner of the Services is based in the state of California in the United States. Our Services are targeted for use only by persons located in the United States. We make no claims that the Services or any of its content is accessible or appropriate outside of the United States. 

24\. Age Restriction. You must be 13 years of age or older to visit or use the Services in any manner. If under the age of 18 or the age of majority as that is defined in your jurisdiction, you must use any Services under the supervision of a parent, legal guardian, or other responsible adult.

25\. Disclaimer of Warranties. You understand that we cannot and do not guarantee or warrant that files available for downloading from the internet or the Services will be free of viruses or other destructive code. You are responsible for implementing sufficient procedures and checkpoints to satisfy your particular requirements for anti-virus protection and accuracy of data input and output, and for maintaining a means external to our site for any reconstruction of any lost data. 

NEOGOV SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES, COSTS, EXPENSES OR OTHER CONSEQUENCES INCURRED BY YOU OR ANY OTHER PERSON OR ENTITY AS A RESULT OF DELAY IN OR INABILITY TO DELIVER ANY SERVICESS DUE TO CIRCUMSTANCES OR EVENTS BEYOND NEOGOV’s REASONABLE CONTROL, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION: (A) ACTS OF GOD; (B) CHANGES IN OR IN THE INTERPRETATION OF ANY LAW, RULE, REGULATION, OR ORDINANCE; (C) STRIKES, LOCKOUTS, OR OTHER LABOR PROBLEMS; (D) TRANSPORTATION DELAYS; (E) UNAVAILABILITY OF SUPPLIES OR MATERIALS; (F) FIRE OR EXPLOSION; (G) RIOT, MILITARY ACTION, OR USURPED POWER; OR (H) ACTIONS OR FAILURES TO ACT ON THE PART OF A GOVERNMENTAL AUTHORITY.

NEOGOV DOES NOT AND CANNOT CONTROL THE FLOW OF DATA TO OR FROM THE NEOGOV SERVICES AND OTHER PORTIONS OF THE INTERNET. SUCH FLOW DEPENDS IN LARGE PART ON THE PERFORMANCE OF INTERNET SERVICES PROVIDED OR CONTROLLED BY THIRD PARTIES. AT TIMES, ACTIONS OR INACTIONS OF SUCH THIRD PARTIES CAN IMPAIR OR DISRUPT YOUR CONNECTIONS TO THE INTERNET (OR PORTIONS THEREOF). ALTHOUGH NEOGOV WILL USE COMMERCIALLY REASONABLE EFFORTS TO TAKE ALL ACTIONS IT DEEMS APPROPRIATE TO REMEDY AND AVOID SUCH EVENTS, NEOGOV CANNOT GUARANTEE THAT SUCH EVENTS WILL NOT OCCUR. ACCORDINGLY, NEOGOV DISCLAIMS ANY AND ALL LIABILITY RESULTING FROM OR RELATED TO SUCH EVENTS.

YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES, ITS CONTENT, AND ANY SERVICES OR ITEMS OBTAINED THROUGH THE SERVICES IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. THE SERVICES, ITS CONTENT, AND ANY SERVICES OR ITEMS OBTAINED THROUGH THE SERVICES ARE PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" AND "AS AVAILABLE" BASIS, WITHOUT ANY WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED. NEITHER NEOGOV NOR ANY PERSON ASSOCIATED WITH NEOGOV MAKES ANY WARRANTY OR REPRESENTATION WITH RESPECT TO THE COMPLETENESS, SECURITY, RELIABILITY, QUALITY, ACCURACY, OR AVAILABILITY OF THE SERVICES. WITHOUT LIMITING THE FOREGOING, NEITHER NEOGOV NOR ANYONE ASSOCIATED WITH NEOGOV REPRESENTS OR WARRANTS THAT THE SERVICES, ITS CONTENT, OR ANY SERVICES OR ITEMS OBTAINED THROUGH THE SERVICES WILL BE ACCURATE, RELIABLE, ERROR-FREE, OR UNINTERRUPTED, THAT DEFECTS WILL BE CORRECTED, THAT OUR SITE OR THE SERVER THAT MAKES IT AVAILABLE ARE FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER HARMFUL COMPONENTS, OR THAT THE SERVICES OR ANY SERVICES OR ITEMS OBTAINED THROUGH THE SERVICES WILL OTHERWISE MEET YOUR NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS.

TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PROVIDED BY LAW, NEOGOV HEREBY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, STATUTORY, OR OTHERWISE, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO ANY WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, NON-INFRINGEMENT, AND FITNESS FOR PARTICULAR PURPOSE. THE FOREGOING DOES NOT AFFECT ANY WARRANTIES THAT CANNOT BE EXCLUDED OR LIMITED UNDER APPLICABLE LAW.

You acknowledge that NEOGOV exercises no control over Customer human resource practices implemented using the Service or decisions as to employment, promotion, termination, or compensation of any Job Seeker or Personnel. You further agree and acknowledge that Customers are responsible for all contact and questions regarding the hiring process. In addition, Customers are responsible for the privacy, collection, use, retention and processing of Customer owned data, and providing any and all notices regarding the foregoing, in compliance with all applicable laws. 

26\. Limitation on Liability. TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, IN NO EVENT SHALL NEOGOV, ITS AFFILIATES, OR THEIR LICENSORS, SERVICE PROVIDERS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, OFFICERS, OR DIRECTORS HAVE ANY LIABILITY TO THE OTHER PARTY OR TO ANY OTHER PERSON OR ENTITY ARISING OUT OF OR RELATED TO THIS AGREEMENT, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, CUSTOMER’S USE OR, OR INABILITY TO USE, THE SERVICES, UNDER ANY CIRCUMSTANCE, CAUSE OF ACTION OR THEORY OF LIABILITY, OR DUE TO ANY EVENT WHATSOEVER, FOR ANY CONSEQUENTIAL, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, PERSONAL INJURY, PAIN AND SUFFERING, EMOTIONAL DISTRESS, LOSS OF REVENUE, LOSS OF BUSINESS OPPORTUNITY OR PROFIT, LOSS OF USE, LOSS OF GOODWILL OR BUSINESS STOPPAGE, LOSS OF DATA, EVEN IF FORESEEABLE OR NEOGOV KNEW OR SHOULD HAVE KNOWN OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.

WITHOUT LIMITATION OF THE FOREGOING, EXCEPT FOR DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF NEOGOV’s GROSS NEGLIGENCE OR WILLFUL MISCONDUCT, THE TOTAL LIABILITY OF NEOGOV, ITS AFFILIATES, OFFICERS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, SUPPLIERS, AND LICENSORS, FOR ANY AND ALL CLAIMS UNDER THIS AGREEMENT SHALL NOT EXCEED ONE HUNDRED ($100.00) U.S. DOLLARS. THE FOREGOING LIMITATION OF LIABILITY IS CUMULATIVE WITH ALL PAYMENTS FOR CLAIMS OR DAMAGES IN CONNECTION WITH THIS AGREEMENT BEING AGGREGATED TO DETERMINE SATISFACTION OF THE LIMIT. THE EXISTENCE OF ONE OR MORE CLAIMS WILL NOT ENLARGE THE LIMIT. THE PARTIES ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT THIS LIMITATION OF LIABILITY IS AN ESSENTIAL ELEMENT OF THE BASIS OF THE BARGAIN BETWEEN THE PARTIES AND SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING THE FAILURE OF THE ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY LIMITED REMEDY. EACH PARTY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THIS LIMITATION OF LIABILITY REFLECTS AN INFORMED, VOLUNTARY ALLOCATION BETWEEN THE PARTIES OF THE RISKS (KNOWN AND UNKNOWN) THAT MAY EXIST IN CONNECTION WITH THIS AGREEMENT AND HAS BEEN TAKEN INTO ACCOUNT AND REFLECTED IN DETERMINING THE CONSIDERATION TO BE GIVEN BY EACH PARTY UNDER THIS AGREEMENT AND IN THE DECISION BY EACH PARTY TO ENTER INTO THIS AGREEMENT.

THE FOREGOING DOES NOT AFFECT ANY LIABILITY THAT CANNOT BE EXCLUDED OR LIMITED UNDER APPLICABLE LAW.

27\. Indemnification. To the extent permitted by law, You agree to defend, indemnify, and hold harmless NEOGOV, its affiliates, licensors, and service providers, and its and their respective officers, directors, employees, contractors, agents, licensors, suppliers, successors, and assigns from and against any claims, liabilities, damages, judgments, awards, losses, costs, expenses, or fees (including reasonable attorneys’ fees) arising out of or relating to your violation of these Terms of Use or your use of the Services, including, but not limited to, your User Contributions, any use of the Services’ content, services, and products other than as expressly authorized in these Terms of Use or your use of any information obtained from the Services.

28\. Governing Law and Jurisdiction. All matters relating to the Services and these Terms of Use and any dispute or claim arising therefrom or related thereto (in each case, including non-contractual disputes or claims), shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the internal laws of the State of California without giving effect to any choice or conflict of law provision or rule (whether of the State of California or any other jurisdiction). Any legal suit, action, or proceeding arising out of, or related to, these Terms of Use or the Services shall be instituted exclusively in the federal courts of the United States or the courts of the State of California in each case located in the City of Los Angeles and County of Los Angeles although we retain the right to bring any suit, action, or proceeding against you for breach of these Terms of Use in your country of residence or any other relevant country. You waive any and all objections to the exercise of jurisdiction over you by such courts and to venue in such courts.

29\. Arbitration. At our sole discretion, we may require you to submit any disputes arising from the use of these Terms of Use or the Services, including disputes arising from or concerning their interpretation, violation, invalidity, non-performance, or termination, to final and binding arbitration under the Rules of Arbitration of the American Arbitration Association applying California law.

30\. Waiver and Severability. No waiver by NEOGOV of any term or condition set out in these Terms of Use shall be deemed a further or continuing waiver of such term or condition or a waiver of any other term or condition, and any failure of NEOGOV to assert a right or provision under these Terms of Use shall not constitute a waiver of such right or provision. If any provision of these Terms of Use is held by a court or other tribunal of competent jurisdiction to be invalid, illegal, or unenforceable for any reason, such provision shall be eliminated or limited to the minimum extent such that the remaining provisions of the Terms of Use will continue in full force and effect.

31\. Entire Agreement and Assignment. Unless otherwise stipulated, the Terms of Use, Privacy Policy, and documents incorporated herein constitute the sole and entire agreement between you and Governmentjobns.com, Inc. regarding the Services and supersede all prior and contemporaneous understandings, agreements, representations, and warranties, both written and oral, regarding the Services. You may not assign any part of this Terms of Use without NEOGOV’s prior written consent. No waiver of any obligation or right of either party shall be effective unless in writing, executed by the party against whom it is being enforced.

32\. Your Comments and Concerns. 

This website is operated by Governmentjobs.com, Inc. with offices at 300 Continental Blvd., Suite 565, El Segundo, CA 90245. 

For further information relating to the legal issues contained in these Terms or problem reports regarding this service, please contact using the following:

If you are a Job Seeker, please contact: [support@GovernmentJobs.com](mailto:support@GovernmentJobs.com)

If you are a Customer (an organization), please contact: [customersupport@GovernmentJobs.com](mailto:customersupport@GovernmentJobs.com)

## **_Our Commitment to Privacy_**

Governmentjobs.com, Inc. (DBA “NEOGOV” and referred to herein as “we”, or “us”) is committed to protecting your privacy and providing transparency regarding use of your information. We consider information privacy throughout our product lifecycle - from inception, to production, and ongoing support.

## **_Services_**

The principal purpose of this Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) is to describe our collection, use, and disclosure of personal information we collect about users of [www.neogov.com](http://www.neogov.com/), [www.governmentjobs.com](http://www.governmentjobs.com/), and the subdomains and subdirectories of each (collectively referred to as the “Services” for purposes of this Policy), but excluding services that state that they are offered under a different privacy policy.

By visiting or using any part of the Services you agree that your personal information will be processed as described in this Policy. Where required by law, additional consent is obtained before personal information is transferred to us or forwarded to other parties.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into the Governmentjobs.com Terms of Use. Definitions not explicitly defined herein shall retain the meaning as prescribed in the Terms of Use. Any dispute related to privacy is subject to the Terms of Use and this Policy, including limitations on liability.

## **_Who “You” Are._**

Who “you” are defined as within this Privacy Policy will change the rights and responsibilities with respect to personal information. To help describe who you are, the following definitions explain the different relationships that arise when users access our Services.

  * **Customer** : You are an employer or agent of an employer that pays for access to our Services for posting job solicitations, recruitment, hiring, onboarding personnel, performance monitoring, training, or other applicable HR services provided by us.
  * **Personnel** : You are Personnel if a Customer stores information about you in a Service, including if you are a Job Applicant. 
  * **Job Seeker** : You hold a Job Seeker account with one or more of our Services for the purpose of receiving and responding to job solicitations. Once you submit a job application to a Customer, you are considered a “Job Applicant” for that Customer.
  * **Visitor** : You are just visiting one of our Services.

## **_Data Controllers_**

Our Customers use our Services to post job opportunities, evaluate Job Applicants, manage their human resource activities, and train their workforce. In conducting these activities, the Customer maintains control over what information is collected, how it is used, how long it is retained, and who it is disclosed to. For purposes of the EU GDPR, the Customer is considered a data controller in these respects and NEOGOV is a data processor. In other instances, such as when NEOGOV uses cookies or sends you correspondence about our Services, NEOGOV will determine the means and purpose of processing.

## **_Information We Collect About You._**

We require certain personal information in order to provide you Services, and automatically collect other information during your usage. In this Section we set out general categories of personal information and data we may collect and process.

  * **Usage Data.** We may process data about your use of our Services ("Usage Data"). Usage data is gathered automatically when you visit the Services. This information may include webpages visited, what you click on, and when and how you perform those actions.

  * **Account Data.** We may process your account data ("Account Data"). Account data may include your name, email address, unique account ID, password, and various preferences. You might provide us with your Account Data through use of our Services, an online inquiry, interaction with our sales or support teams, or a survey response.

  * **Profile Data.** We may process Job Seeker and Personnel personal information related to employment included in your within your account. For Job Seekers, Profile Data be created independently during a job application, or through a third party such as Facebook. Profile Data personal information will depend on who you are. For instance, typical personal information for a Job Seeker or Personnel may include first and last name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, resume, driver’s license, work experience, education history, and any other supplemental information added at your discretion. Customer Profile Data may include personal information of multiple Job Seekers and Personnel, based upon the information that Customer chooses to collect and maintain.

  * **Log Data.** Our servers maintain log files that document each time a device accesses those servers (“Log Data”). The logs include information about the nature of each access, the IP address, ISP, the files viewed on our Services, Account Data, preference and content changes in certain cases, operating systems, device type and timestamps.

  * **Device Data.** We may process information about your device or how you access our Services (“Device Data”). Device Data may include Internet protocol (IP) address, browser type, device type, software and hardware attributes, information pages visited, referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site, your operating system, system and performance information, cookie date/time stamp, search terms entered on the site, and clickstream data.

  * **Publication Data.** We may process information that you post for publication on our website or through our Services ("Publication Data").

  * **Inquiry and Contact Data.** We may process information contained in any inquiry and contact information you submit to us regarding the Services, support, in response to a survey, or interaction with our sales team (“Inquiry and Contact Data”).

  * **Tracking Data.** We use tracking services that employ cookies and web beacons to collect user statistics and usage about visitors of our Services and receipt of communications (“Tracking Data”).

  * **Transaction and Billing Data.** We may allow payment processing companies to process information relating to transactions, including purchases of Services, that you enter on the Services or payment processor website ("Transaction Data"). If you make an online payment to us through a payment processing company, we require you to provide your billing details, a name, address, email address and financial information corresponding to your selected method of payment (e.g. a credit card number and expiration date or a bank account number)(“Billing Data”).

  * **Integration Data.** With your permission or where you have made it publicly available online, we collect and disclose information to and from third party integrators to facilitate such services (“Integration Data”). Depending on who you are, this information may include Account Data, Transaction or Billing Data, Profile Data, Device Data, processing status, and URLs to full reports.

  * **Correspondence Data.** We may process information contained in or relating to any communication you send us (“Correspondence Data”). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication.

## **_Our Use of Your Information._**

We will collect personal information by lawful and fair means with your knowledge and where appropriate, your consent. Personal information will only be processed for purposes stated herein, where you have provided consent, or as required by law or regulation - including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

For personal information subject to GDPR, we rely on multiple legal bases for processing, including:

  * Consent (which can be revoked by utilizing privacy controls, deleting Profile or Account Data, or contacting support)

  * When processing is necessary to perform a contract (e.g. delivering you the Services)

  * Legitimate business interests such as developing the Services, marketing new features or products, proper administration of our website and business, ensuring safety and security

  * Where necessary to protect vital or public interests

  * As required by law

In this section we set out the purposes for which we may process information, and legal bases of the processing.

## **_Use of Job Seeker Information._**

We process the information about you with your consent, in order to fulfill our contractual responsibility to deliver you the Services or pursue our legitimate interests of improving the experience in our Services or developing new products and service features.

We collect and use the following information on the basis that we have to use this information to fulfill our contract with you.

  * **Account Data.** We use your Account Data to run your account, provide you Services, maintain your user preferences, bill you for use of our Services if applicable, ensure the security of our Services, to detect and prevent activities that violate our policies or the law, maintain back-ups of our databases, provide you support, send you notices, and contact you about your account status. You cannot opt out of this use since they are required to provide you our Services. 

Example: We may use your email associated with your account or your account ID to notify you about service related announcements, the status of your background check or job application, and about changes to the services or policies.

  * **Profile Data.** We use information within your Job Seeker account, including your personal information you input via web forms or attachments, in order to provide you our Services, make your Profile viewable by potential employers, and transfer your job applications to our Customers (your potential employers). In addition, in the legitimate interest of providing you a personalized and efficient experience.

  * **Correspondence Data.** We may use and share Correspondence Data internally in order to provide you our Services and support, to help diagnose problems with our Services, prevent fraud, and implement enhancements contained in or relating to any communication you send us.

  * **Transaction and Billing Data.** If you make a payment through the Services, we use and collect your billing details and metadata about the transaction from our third-party providers for finance and accounting purposes, and to ensure the Services you pay for are those you have access to.

  * **Integration Data.** We collect and use information from our affiliated third parties and Integration partners to ensure you can use our Services in conjunction with other services and facilitate your use of Integrations. 

Example: Integrations may include payment processing companies, background check and online assessment providers, communication providers. We use your name, zip code, phone number, employment history, education history, and email address to facilitate your use of background check or assessment company services.

We use Tracking and Log Data on our Services.

  * **Tracking Data.** We collect information from page tags and web beacons to allow us to determine the success of our advertising campaigns.

  * **Log Data.** We use Log Data for many different business purposes, including: 
    * To monitor abuse and troubleshoot
    * To track your preferences
    * To create new services, features, content or make personalized recommendations
    * To track behavior at the aggregate/anonymous level to identify and understand trends in the various interactions with our services
    * To fix bugs and troubleshoot product functionality
    * Your IP address is used to determine where an unknown/unauthorized access may have occurred in your account (abuse monitoring)
    * We also collect log data to collate aggregated data and metrics on activity at a non-identifying level so that we can identify trends in job applications over time

We process your personal information in the following categories for our legitimate interests. We take steps to ensure we place limitations on each of these uses so your privacy is respected and only the information necessary to achieve these legitimate aims is used. 

  * **Inquiry and Contact Data.** We use contact information to respond to your inquiries, and send you notices regarding your application status. 

Example: We use your email address to send you notices, updates on your account, about significant changes to the services, and newsletters (unless you opt-out). In addition, our support team will use your email address to communicate with you if you have contacted us. You can change your email preferences to control notifications you receive from us and Customers or unsubscribe from a notification by following instructions contained within the notification itself, or your account settings.

  * **Usage Data.** We may use information about how you use and interact with our Services to analyze trends, for internal system administration, to help diagnose problems with our servers, prevent fraud, and determine and implement enhancements. 

Example: We combine information about you from your use of the Services with other information to make inferences, use aggregated and de-personalized characteristics about you in order to provide you insights into your use and our Customers’ use of the Services, and recommend you to Customers.

  * **Device Data.** We use device data both to troubleshoot problems with our Services and make improvements. We also infer your geographic location based on your IP address. 

Example: We collect attributes about the software and hardware you use to access the Services to troubleshoot and fix bugs, optimize the Services for particular devices and browsers, and to ensure the Services are accessible.

Using the data mentioned above, we combine information about you from third party sources with information we hold about you to and use machine learning techniques Log, Device, and Tracking Data in order to provide Customers with useful and relevant insights from the data they have collected using our Services, to build features, improve our Services and to develop aggregated data products.

  * To manage our services we will also internally use your information and data, for the following limited purposes: 
    * To enforce our agreements where applicable
    * To prevent potentially illegal activities
    * To screen for and prevent undesirable or abusive activity. For example, we have automated systems that screen content for phishing activities, spam, and fraud

  * **Legal uses.** To respond to legal requests or prevent fraud, we may need to disclose any information or data we hold about you. If we receive a subpoena or other legal request, we may need to inspect the data we hold to determine how to respond.

## **_Use of Job Applications._**

In general job applications and other information submit to Customers are controlled and managed by the Customer (the potential or current employer who sent or deployed that job solicitation). In those instances NEOGOV is only processing those applications on behalf of the Customer. Our legal obligations as a processor are set out in our Customer contracts, policies, or via internet privacy frameworks.

If you apply to a job, make your Job Seeker Profile viewable to Customers, provide information to show interest in a job, or reply to a message from a Customer, you consent to disclosing your information to Customer(s) for their Personnel to complete recruitment and hiring processes and to contact you, including for future job opportunities.

Our goal is to improve the user experience across our Services while maintaining the confidentiality and privacy of users.

## **_Use of Customer and Personnel information._**

We process the information about you and the Job Seeker or Personnel personal information you maintain with us with your consent, in order to fulfill our contractual responsibility to deliver you the Services or pursue our legitimate interests of improving the experience in our Services or developing new products and service features.

We collect and use the following information on the basis that we have to use this information to fulfill our contract with you.

  * **Account Data.** We use your Account Data to run your account, provide you our Services, maintain your preferences, bill you for use of our Services, provide you Customer support, and contact you about your account. Based on your user access level and the purpose of use, you cannot opt out of this use since they are required to provide you our Services. 

Example: We may use your email associated with your account or your account ID to notify you about service related announcements, billing related matters, changes to the services or policies, welcome emails.

  * **Profile Data.** We process other information within your account, including the personal information you collect on Job Seekers and your Personnel, in order to provide you our Services. In addition, in the legitimate interest of providing you a personalized and efficient experience.

  * **Publication Data.** We use information you post for publication on the Services to facilitate your HR and hiring processes, to troubleshoot problems with our Services, and as feedback for improvement to the Services.

  * **Correspondence Data.** We may use and share internally Correspondence Data in order to provide you our Services and support, to help diagnose problems with our Services, prevent fraud, and implement enhancements contained in or relating to any communication you send us.

  * **Transaction and Billing Data.** If you make a payment through the Services, we use and collect your billing details and metadata about the transaction from our third-party providers for finance and accounting purposes, and to ensure the Services you pay for are those you have access to.

  * **Integration Data.** We collect and use information from our affiliated third parties and Integration partners to ensure you can use our Services in conjunction with other services and facilitate your use of Integrations. 

Example: Integrations may include payment processing companies, background check and online assessment providers, communication providers, or HR related services you choose to integrate our Services with (collectively the “Integrations”). We use your name, zip code, phone number, employment history, education history, and email address to facilitate your use of background check or assessment company services. We use links and percentages in our Services to display background and testing results and provide access to more detailed results.

We use Tracking and Log Data on our Services.

  * **Tracking Data.** We collect information from page tags and web beacons to allow us to determine the success of our advertising campaigns.

  * **Log Data.** We use Log Data for many different business purposes, including: 
    * To monitor abuse and troubleshoot
    * To track your preferences
    * To create new services, features, content or make personalized recommendations
    * To track behavior at the aggregate/anonymous level to identify and understand trends in the various interactions with our services
    * To fix bugs and troubleshoot product functionality
    * Your IP address is used to determine where an unknown/unauthorized access may have occurred in your account (abuse monitoring)

We process your personal information in the following categories for our legitimate interests. We take steps to ensure we place limitations on each of these uses so your privacy is respected and only the information necessary to achieve these legitimate aims is used. 

  * **Inquiry and Contact Data.** We use contact information to respond to your support, product, and transaction inquiries, to send you information as part of the Services, relevant notifications, newsletters, surveys, status on payment receipts, marketing our products and features (for as long as you do not opt-out), or providing you information on Job Seekers to provide you and send marketing information. 

Example: We use your email address to send you newsletters (unless you opt-out), for general updates on your account, for significant changes made to your preferences or issues requiring your action. You can opt-out of marketing communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” changing your account settings or using your email provider preferences.

  * **Usage Data.** We may process information about how you use and interact with our Services to analyze trends, for internal system administration and provision of Services, determine country of origin, identify clickstreams that led you to our Services, to help diagnose problems with our servers, prevent fraud, and determine and implement enhancements. 

Example: We combine information about you from your use of the Services with other information to make inferences about your HR processes, including your hiring process, how long it takes to complete the process, what Service features you are using to complete the process. We also use aggregated and de-personalized characteristics about the Job Seekers and Personnel you maintain information about in order to provide you insights into your use of the Services and your HR processes.

  * **Device Data.** We use device data both to troubleshoot problems with our Services and make improvements. We also infer your geographic location based on your IP address. 

Example: We collect attributes about the software and hardware you use to access the Services to troubleshoot and fix bugs, optimize the Services for particular devices and browsers, and to ensure the Services are accessible.

Using the data mentioned above, we combine information about you from third party sources with information we hold about you to create a profile, which will help us to make our sales and marketing efforts more relevant to you and to personalize and improve our marketing campaigns and Service experiences. We also use machine learning techniques on certain data in order to optimize our marketing campaigns.

  * To manage our services we will also internally use your information and data, for the following limited purposes: 
    * To enforce our agreements where applicable
    * To prevent potentially illegal activities
    * To screen for and prevent undesirable or abusive activity. For example, we have automated systems that screen content for phishing activities, spam, and fraud

  * **Legal uses.** To respond to legal requests or prevent fraud, we may need to disclose any information or data we hold about you. If we receive a subpoena or other legal request, we may need to inspect the data we hold to determine how to respond.

## **_Use of Visitor information._**

We process personal information about you where you have consented or where we have legitimate interests in improving our services and developing new products and service features.

We collect and use the following information about you:

  * **Inquiry and Contact Data.** We use inquiry and contact information to respond to your inquiries, send you information about the Services, send you marketing information (as long as you haven’t opted out), send you relevant notifications, newsletters, surveys, and marketing our Services and features. 

Example: A sales member will use an email address you provided us regarding an inquiry you submitted in one of our online forms. Another example is marketing communications from us, of which you will have the opportunity to opt-out process information contained in any inquiry and contact information you submit to us regarding the Services, support, in response to a survey, or interaction with our sales team.

  * **Tracking Data.** We collect information from page tags and web beacons to allow us to determine the success of our advertising campaigns and what pages you click on when visiting our marketing pages. We also use page tags to allow the email sender (for a survey or form for example) to measure the performance of their email messaging and to learn how to improve email deliverability and open rates.

  * **Usage Data.** We may process information about how you use and interact with our Services to analyze trends, to help diagnose problems with our servers, prevent fraud, and identify clickstreams that led you to our Services. 

Example: We track feature use to determine what features and processes are most and least popular.

Using the data mentioned above, we combine information about you from third party sources with information we hold about you to create a profile, which will help us to make our sales and marketing efforts more relevant to you and to personalize and improve our marketing campaigns and Service experiences. We also use machine learning techniques on certain data in order to optimize our marketing campaigns.

We process your personal information in the following categories for legitimate interests:

  * **Device Data.** We use device data both to troubleshoot problems with our service and to make improvements. We also infer your geographic location based on your IP address. 

Example: We collect attributes about the software and hardware you use to access the Services to troubleshoot and fix bugs.

  * **Log Data.** We use Log Data for many different business purposes, including: 
    * To monitor abuse and troubleshoot
    * To track your preferences
    * To create new services, features, content or make personalized recommendations
    * To track behavior at the aggregate/anonymous level to identify and understand trends in the various interactions with our services
    * To fix bugs and troubleshoot product functionality

Example: We track feature use to determine what features are taking longer to use than others.

  * To manage our services we will use your information and data internally, for the following limited purposes: 
    * To enforce agreements
    * To prevent illegal activities
    * To screen and prevent abusive activity. For example, phishing activities, spam, and fraud

  * **Legal uses.** To respond to legal requests or prevent fraud, we may need to disclose any information or data we hold about you. If we receive a subpoena or other legal request, we may need to inspect the data we hold to determine how to respond.

## **_Information We Share._**

The information we gather may be share with the following third parties:

  * Customers, when a Job Seeker makes their profile information searchable or apply to a job
  * Partners and vendors hired to provide services on our behalf
  * Other third parties where required by law
  * Other third parties when you give your consent to such sharing

We do not share your personal information with third parties outside of NEOGOV except in circumstances described herein. For processing based on consent, Personal information will not be disclosed to third parties for new uses or purposes unless you have given secondary, prior consent.

If you are a Job Seeker, we share the information you submit to Customers for the purpose of evaluating your for potential job opportunities.

To help us provide certain aspects of our services we use our affiliates and partners to:

  * facilitate our email collectors for sending surveys by email to Customers and Job Seekers
  * facilitate your use of the Services
  * facilitate Customers in making credit card payments
  * deliver and help us track our marketing and advertising content
  * Facilitate and deliver payroll processing and disbursements
  * help us track website conversion success metrics
  * manage our sales, support, and Customer support services

We enter into confidentiality and data processing terms with partners that receive personal information to ensure they comply with high levels of confidentiality and best practice in privacy and security standards and we review these standards and practices.

We share certain personal information or data if you choose to use an Integration in conjunction with our Services, to the extent necessary to facilitate that use. More specifically, the following Integrations may send and receive personal information with us:

  * Integrations may include payment processing companies, background check and online assessment providers, communication providers, or third-party services Customer chooses to utilize our open API with. For example: 
    * We may process your information for background check services. This data may include a URL to the full background check report (which requires login to the third-party system), current status of the background check report (pending, clear, or review), and we may send your name, zip code, phone number, employment history, education history, and email address to facilitate your use of the service with the background check company. The source of this data is you and the background check company. You have a right to information the background check company retains on you, and you may request a copy from the background check company you use.
    * We may process online assessment information. This data may include assessment scores/percentages, and URLs to the full assessment results (which require login to the third-party system). This data may be processed for facilitating access to the full assessment and communicating applicant assessment results to you and the Customer who requested administration of the assessment.
    * Financial transactions relating to our website and services are handled by our payment services providers, CyberSource (VISA), JP Morgan Chase, Merchant e-Solutions, Stripe, and Braintree. We will use and share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds.
    * Customers can use our Open API to integrate our Services with their other HR-related services for a smooth flow of data across their internal products. What personal information is shared with these third parties is at the discretion and control of the Customer.

We also have to share personal information or data in order to:

  * meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request
  * enforce applicable policies, including investigation of potential violations
  * detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues
  * protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of our users, the public or to NEOGOV and/or as required or permitted by law
  * protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person
  * where disclosure is necessary for establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims or where there is reasonable belief that disclosure is required by law or regulations
  * transfer personal information to a third party who acquires any or all of our business units, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets

We may share non-personal information with affiliated partners and use machine learning techniques on tracking and metadata in order to provide Customers with useful insights from the data they collected using Services, to build or enhance features, improve Services, and improve infrastructure and security.

We may also share personal information where you provide your consent.

Internally, we restrict access to personal information to essential employees and third parties on a “need to know” basis.

During your use of the Services you may have the opportunity to visit or link to other websites, including websites by third parties unaffiliated with us. We have no relationship or control over unaffiliated websites. These websites might collect personal information about you, and you should review the privacy policies of such other websites to see how they treat your personal information. Use of such websites are at your own risk.

## **_Your Rights and Control under EU GDPR._**

European residents or individuals whose information we receive under the EU-US Privacy Shield have legal rights to determine whether we hold personal information about them, to access personal information we hold about them, and to obtain its correction, update, amendment, or deletion in appropriate circumstances. In particular, your rights may include:

  * Data Access Rights
  * Right to Restrict Processing
  * Right of Rectification
  * Right to be Forgotten
  * Right to Object to Processing
  * Right to Withdraw Consent; and
  * Data Portability Rights

Some of these rights may be subject to exception and limitation. In any case, we will respond to your request to exercise these rights within a reasonable time but no later than within 30 days of receiving a request. To request to exercise your rights, you may contact us at [privacy@governmentjobs.com](mailto:privacy@governmentjobs.com). Some of the rights are complex, and you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights. You may also have the right to make a GDPR complaint to the relevant Supervisory Authority. A list of Supervisory Authorities is available here: <https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en>

## **_Job Seeker Rights._**

You can review and enforce your personal information rights through your Job Seeker account, communications you receive from us, or with the assistance of our support team.

If you apply to a job through a job board powered by us (e.g. Governmentjobs.com, Career Pages, Schooljobs.com, Agency pages) to make applying to future jobs on our Services easier, you create a universal account that persists on www.governmentjobs.com. This account will include your basic profile information. You have the right to delete this universal Governmemtjobs.com account, or any other Job Seeker account you hold, by logging in and following the deletion steps in the account settings.

You have the right to have any inaccurate personal information about you rectified. You can modify or delete personal information within your Job Seeker Profile at any time by logging in to your applicable account and following the prompts to either “update my profile” or “delete my profile.”

Our Services incorporate privacy controls which allow you to specify and limit how we process some of your personal information. For instance, to limit use of your email address, or place global limits on which Customers can preview your Job Seeker Profile, log into your account on [https://www.governmentjobs.com](https://www.governmentjobs.com/) and go to your account settings. Job Seekers can utilize similar privacy controls on a per Customer basis in each Career Page account created.

You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal information and, where we do, access to the personal information. To see whether information on you is retained on our servers, please visit click here. Certain Job Seekers are entitled to request copies of their personal information held by us. You can print a copy of your Profile information using your web browser and download your attachments at any time by logging into your account and following the download process.

To the extent the basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time by using the privacy controls in your account settings or within certain correspondence you receive, by deleting personal information within your Job Seeker Profile, or by deleting your account. If you revoke your consent by deleting your account, your Profile information will be removed from our Job Seeker server, as well as any personal information we shared or received from our affiliated Integrators you utilized; however, revoking your consent will not remove applications you previously submit to Customers.

Upon submission of your application or making your personal information available to one of our Customers (your potential employer), your application becomes the property of the Customer. We are a data processor of Customer information in this regard, and we are not in a position to directly handle data requests for data owned by Customers. Customers may store personal information they receive from you on our servers or their own storage facilities. Customers control the types of personal information requested from you, and how long they retain this personal information. If you would like to learn what personal information Customers maintain about you, access, review, or correct that personal information, you should contact the Customer with any such inquiry. We will cooperate with such inquiry to the extent it is permitted under our confidentiality and privacy obligations.

For inquiries related to resetting your account, if you want to request a restriction or limitation in how we use your personal information, or if you believe someone else has gained access to your account or provided us your contact information, please contact support at: [support@GovernmentJobs.com](mailto:support@GovernmentJobs.com)

## **_Customer and Personnel Rights._**

We are a data processor for personal information Customers’ maintain about Job Seekers and Personnel in our servers. This personal information is Customer property and we maintain limited rights to such data in order to process as necessary to deliver the Services or support to Customers’, to ensure safety and security of our Services, where necessary to protect vital public interests, or as required by law.

Customers are entitled to access, correct, update or delete the Job Seeker and Personnel personal data we hold on the Customers’ behalf and may do so at any time by logging into your account, subject to your access rights. You may download or export most of the personal information you collect through the Services, via the Services. To the extent this section conflicts with specifically agreed contractual terms with you elsewhere, such contract terms those terms shall control.

Personnel rights are subject to Customer internal policies and applicable law. Personnel should contact the Customer (their employer or previous employer) regarding personal information the Customer may hold about them and to exercise any legal rights they may have.

## **_Visitor Rights._**

If you visited our website and you want to exercise any of the above rights please contact our support team or privacy team at the contacts listed herein. If your request is for the right to be forgotten as it relates to our use of cookies, you can achieve this by clearing the cookies in your browser settings.

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our visitors who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at [privacy@governmentjobs.com](mailto:privacy@governmentjobs.com).

## **_Retention and Removal._**

We retain your personal information for as long as your account is considered active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person, and enforce our agreements.

Our retention policies and procedures are designed to help ensure our compliance with legal obligations and allow Customers to comply with their own record retention requirements. We implement retention controls Customers can utilize within the Services to control their data retention periods.

For personal information we determine the purposes for and means by which it is processed, such information will not be kept for longer than necessary for the purpose, when no longer relevant, or upon permissible request, and will be appropriately disposed in a manner designed to ensure it cannot be reconstructed or read.

If you are located in the European Union and you do not sign in to your account or interact with our Services for more than five years, your account will expire and be scheduled for removal from our site.

Upon your deletion of your account or any data point within the Job Seeker account or Profile, it will be removed from our Job Seeker database subject to the remainder of this section, but applications you previously submit to Customers will persist until Customer disposal. Put differently, once a Job Seeker sends an application to a Customer using our Services, that Customer will control access and modification rights to that application, as well as the retention period. Job Seekers should contact the Customer they sent the application to if they seek enforcement of eligible data rights in that application.

We may retain your personal information even after you have closed your account if reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations, meet regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, investigate security incidents, prevent fraud and abuse, enforce our contractual agreements, or fulfill your request to “unsubscribe” from further messages from us. We will retain anonymized information after your account has been closed.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser and device you use to access our Services. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies. A persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

We and our partners use cookies on our Services. Insofar as those cookies are not necessary for the provision of our Services, or the legitimate interests of delivering and optimizing our Services, we receive your consent to use of cookies when you first visit our Services. When your browser or device allows it, we use both session cookies and persistent cookies for the following purposes:

  * **Authentication** to identify you when you visit our Services, as you navigate our Services, to confirm whether you are currently logged in, and determine if an occurrence affects you.
  * **Metrics** to determine how you use the Services, what features you utilize and how often, how much time you spend on the Services and features, and other details about the hiring and HR process. This data is aggregated and anonymized.
  * **Personalization** to store information about your preferences and personalize our Services to you, including to supply Customers with details about their hiring processes, and provide job recommendations to Job Seekers and Customers based on their past interest.
  * **Security** to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials and to protect our Services generally.
  * **Advertising and feedback** to determine whether our advertising and feedback inquiries are received, opened, if the content or campaign is effective, and to provide you more specific content about Services we or our partners offer.
  * **Analysis** to help us analyze the use and performance of our Services, and display different versions of features or content, all of which helps us determine what parts of our Services need improvement and which ones you enjoy most (which may include marketing content).
  * **Google Analytics and Adsense** to analyze the use of our Services and publish advertisements. Google's use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

You can opt out of third-party vendor use of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). In addition, most browsers allow you to refuse to accept or delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser. Please refer to your browser instructions on how to manage your cookies. Blocking all or some cookies may have a negative impact upon the usability of the Services. We do not respond to the browser “Do Not Track” signal if enabled by the end user in their web browser. When third parties we integrate with set or read their own third-party cookies, they may or may not respond to the DNT signal.

## **_Data Security and Integrity._**

We implement physical, technical, and administrative safeguards to maintain data accuracy, integrity, and security, prevent unauthorized access, and facilitate correct use of personal information. These safeguards include limiting access to data, storing personal information on secure servers and computers, encrypting personal information at rest and in transit, periodically testing our security technology, and training our employees in information security. **You are responsible for keeping your username and password secret at all times.**

In addition, we maintain contractual data security and privacy obligations with our partners and vendors, and our employees that have access to Customer and Job Seeker personal information are subject to access, use, and confidentiality policies. Only authorized employees with a reasonable need related to their job duties have access to Customer and Job Seeker personal information. Employees who violate our policies are subject to disciplinary action, up to and including termination. More information about our security controls can be found in our security statements.

In the event we believe the security of your personal information in our possession or control may be compromised, we may seek to notify you by e-mail and you consent to our use of e-mail as a means of such notification.

## **_Information on Children._**

These Services are not directed at children under the age of thirteen (13) and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen (13). If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a Visitor under the age of thirteen (13), we will delete the information from our records. If you believe that we have collected personal information from a child under 13 without parental consent, you may report this to us at [privacy@governmentjobs.com](mailto:privacy@governmentjobs.com).

## **_Privacy Shield._**

Governmentjobs.com, Inc complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. Governmentjobs.com, Inc has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and data subject rights under the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

We will provide an individual opt-out choice, or opt-in for sensitive data, before we share your data with third parties other than our agents, or before we use it for a purpose other than which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. To request to limit the use and disclosure of your personal information, please submit a written request to [privacy@governmentjobs.com](mailto:privacy@governmentjobs.com).

In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Governmentjobs.com, Inc. also complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal information from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

When Governmentjobs.com, Inc. receives personal information under the Privacy Shield and then transfers it to a third-party service provider acting as agent, Governmentjobs.com, Inc. has certain liability under the Privacy Shield if both (i) the agent processes the information in a manner inconsistent with the Governmentjobs.com, Inc. and (ii) Governmentjobs.com, Inc. is responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. With respect to personal information received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Governmentjobs.com, Inc. is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.

Governmentjobs.com’s accountability for personal data that it receives in the United States under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Governmentjobs.com remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless Governmentjobs.com proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Governmentjobs.com, Inc commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. European Union and Swiss individuals with Privacy Shield inquiries or complaints should first contact Governmentjobs.com by email at [privacy@governmentjobs.com](mailto:privacy@governmentjobs.com).

Governmentjobs.com, Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers> for more information and to file a complaint. This service is provided free of charge to you.

Governmentjobs.com, Inc. has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland in the context of the employment relationship.

If your Privacy Shield complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See Privacy Shield Annex 1 at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>.

## **_Right to Revise._**

We reserve the right to revise our Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our online information practices or to comply with the law by publishing a new version on our website. In circumstances where we materially change the way in which we collect or use personal information, we materially change the terms of this Privacy Policy, or where personal information is no longer used consistently with a previously named purpose, we will provide notice and publish the new version on our website.

You should periodically check this page to remind yourself of the rights herein.

## **_Contact Details._**

This website is owned and operated by Governmentjobs.com, Inc. (DBA “NEOGOV”). Our principal place of business is at 300 Continental Blvd., El Segundo, CA 90245. You can contact us by email, telephone, or regular mail using the contact information listed herein.

## **_Data Protection Officer and Privacy Contacts._**

If at any time you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to E-mail us at the appropriate contact relative your jurisdiction:
